# SIDDHARTH SINGH

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

# CONTACT DETAILS

Mobile: 0406 467 729 Email: siddharth.s1@outlook.com LinkedIn: @s-iddharth-ingh1 Github: github.com/sid-s1?tab=repositories Portfolio: <u>www.thesiddharthsingh.com</u>

# PERSONAL SUMMARY

A software engineer with a passion for building customer-centric applications. I am always thrilled to explore new technologies and work collaboratively with others. With my experience in both operations and software, I have developed effective communication skills and the flexibility to work with the engineering, design and product teams.

# **KEY COMPETENCIES**

React.js Node.js / Express.js HTML, CSS, JS PostgreSQL Python, Flask Jinja Jest (for TDD) Typescript

# ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

#### General Assembly Australia

Software Engineering Immersive | 2022

### University of New South Wales

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) Mechanical Engineering | 2019

### OTHER PROJECTS

### General Assembly Australia

Wordle - Vanilla JS Project

A twist on the NY Times Wordle that allows as many turns as players desire, and lets them build up their score; while also allowing them two more word-choices when they are close to the end of their attempts.

Technologies Used 
HTML, CSS, JS

Check Demo

# PERSONAL INTERESTS

Philosophy - Stoicism, Metaphysics, Existentialism, Eastern Running - Longest run - half-marathon Weightlifting

Hiking - on a quest to find the best mountains in Australia Podcasting - Game and Grow - playing hard games in a group and talking about profound topics

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

QA Engineer 1
QA Wolf - May 2024 - Present

# Fleet Administration and Logistics Manager GoGet Carshare - October 2019 - May 2024

Managed a fleet of 3000+ vehicles -

- Developed and implemented an operations dashboard to monitor and analyse fleet performance metrics, enabling data-driven decisionmaking and enhancing operational efficiency
- Designed and deployed maintenance, cleaning, and productivity dashboards, offering comprehensive insights into multifaceted performance metrics. These dashboards catalysed data-driven decision-making processes, empowering the team to optimise operations effectively (23% increase in operational productivity and efficiency)
- Utilised an availability dashboard to meticulously monitor fleet performance, ensuring optimal vehicle availability for members while proactively identifying and addressing low-performing assets. Resulted in enhanced customer satisfaction and streamlined operations by minimising downtime and maximising fleet utilisation - overall lowering of unavailability by a factor of 4%, re-claiming lost revenue of ~\$400k annually
- Revamped safety protocols resulting in increased compliance and a reduction in incidents by 10% (\$80k annual savings)
- Led contractor and supplier management initiatives, ensuring seamless collaboration and cost-effective procurement
- Directed a team of 10 professionals responsible for various facets of fleet management, including administration, cleaning/maintenance, and logistics, fostering a collaborative and high-performing work environment
- Identified \$500k of lost revenue in various administrative/systemic problems, and lead the fleet uplift and auditing projects to overhaul the ways of working fleet-wide
- Executed successful fleet procurement and disposal projects, optimising vehicle inventory and facilitating smooth supply-chain management for assets upto \$1M at a time
- Managed vehicle registrations and insurance processes for a fleet of over 3000 vehicles, ensuring compliance with regulatory requirements and minimising risks
- Acting as a key point of contact for fleet operations and compliance, I
  also got the company out of a tough spot by renegotiating the amount
  to be paid to \$8k instead of \$105k, by investigating, collecting,
  organising and demonstrating data justifying our company's position

# WORK EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

# General Assembly - May 2022 - October 2022

- Studying for 16 hours a week while working full-time, to kickstart my career change into software engineering, I committed to study the software engineering bootcamp at General Assembly
- My love of learning and time management skills allowed me to complete the following projects:

### **AppMinder - React/NodeJS Project**

A React/NodeJS app that helps a job applicant organise the details of their applications throughout the recruitment process. They can sort their applications across the four stages of Draft, Applied, Interviewing and Awaiting.

Technologies Used -

- React, ReactDND
- CSS
- NodeJS, Express
- PostgreSQL

### Check Demo

### **Tript - NodeJS Project**

A digital travel diary, allowing users to save details of all their favourite trips, activities & hotels. They can also search trips posted by other users allowing them to find new and exciting places to go. Our team of 3 used Github Projects to create project timeline and break the tasks into tickets.

Technologies Used -

- HTML, CSS, JS
- NodeJS, Express
- PostgreSQL
- Google APIs (Autocomplete, Geocoding, Details, Directions)

#### Check Demo

### **Shopping List | Route Generator - Python | Flask Project**

An app to create a shopping list using stores in the real-world (using Google Maps API) and to generate the shortest route between user's home address and all the stores on their list. Technologies Used -

- HTML, CSS, JS
- Python, Flask, Jinja2
- PostgreSQL
- Google APIs (Autocomplete, Geocoding, Details, Directions)

## Check Demo

### Wordle - Vanilla JS Project

A twist on the NY Times Wordle that allows as many turns as players desire, and lets them build up their score; while also allowing them two more word-choices when they are close to the end of their attempts.

Technologies Used -

HTML, CSS, JS

### Check Demo